hi spring fans welcome to another
嗨，春季粉丝们欢迎来到另一个
installment of spring tips in this
在此安装Spring 提示
installment we're going to talk about
我们将讨论的分期付款
something that is near and dear to my
我亲近的东西
heart something that I wanted to talked
心里我想说的话
about in more depth and more at more
关于更多更深入
detail for a long time and indeed we're
细节已经很长时间了，实际上我们
not even gonna be able to talk about all
甚至都无法谈论所有
of it today I think we're gonna have to
今天，我想我们将不得不
do a second video which is a great
做第二个视频，很棒
problem to have so no problem at all mmm
问题，所以完全没有问题
we're gonna talk about Alibaba in
我们将在谈论阿里巴巴
particular some of the some of the
特别是一些
software that they've made available for
他们提供的软件
developers in the in the sort of
开发人员在
ecosystem to use lets call us muggles
使用的生态系统让我们称呼麻瓜
shall we now if you've ever seen me talk
如果您见过我说话，现在可以了吗
about spring at any length before then
在此之前任何长度的春天
you know I I am quite fond of Alibaba
你知道我很喜欢阿里巴巴
they do some amazing things with spring
他们在春天做一些了不起的事情
Alibaba is a large organization in China
阿里巴巴是中国的大型组织
it's a it would be losery albeit
这是一个失败，尽管
misguided to to kind of like it at
在某种程度上被误导了喜欢
Amazon because that that under sells it
亚马逊，因为那在卖
right at Alibaba is a much more
在阿里巴巴还有更多
interesting organization they're much
有趣的组织，他们很多
more diverse first of all so Alibaba has
首先是更多样化的，所以阿里巴巴拥有
many different companies underneath them
他们下面很多不同的公司
it has been around for for for more than
它已经存在了超过
a decade neither since early 2000s I
自2000年代初期以来的十年
think maybe since the 90s but at least
想想也许是从90年代开始，但至少
at early 2000s and in this time they
在2000年代初，此时
become the largest e-commerce engine in
成为最大的电子商务引擎
an agent certainly in terms of the
一个代理商当然就
catalog they're the largest in the world
目录是世界上最大的
larger than Amazon large in the native
比亚马逊大
everything and if they themselves don't
一切，如果他们自己不
dominate in a particular market then
然后在特定市场上占主导地位
they as often is not in Asia especially
他们通常不在亚洲
have a subordinates or satellite
有下属或卫星
companies that they've acquired or
他们收购的公司或
invested in or started up from whole
从整体上投资或开始
cloth that do so for example in
这样做的布
Southeast Asia it's very common to use
东南亚使用非常普遍
Lozada for example in Singapore or
Lozada，例如在新加坡或
Malaysia and so in that that company is
马来西亚，所以那个公司是
largely controlled now by by Alibaba for
现在基本上由阿里巴巴控制
example and Alibaba have a a a
例子和阿里巴巴都有aaa
particularly interesting network of
特别有趣的网络
companies associated with it there's
与之相关的公司
there's a bunch of companies that are
有很多公司
part of Alibaba itself so for example
阿里巴巴本身的一部分，例如
Taobao and Alipay
淘宝和支付宝
and a lien which is the ally cloud all
留置权是盟军的全部
these are Alibaba proper but then others
这些是阿里巴巴合适的，但是其他的
and financial which is not strictly
和财务不严格
speaking
请讲
Alibaba but it's got a it's under the
阿里巴巴，但它有一个
same sort of family because of
同一个家庭，因为
investments from the leadership
领导层的投资
and and then you've got like I said
然后你就像我说的
satellite companies like lazada which
像lazada这样的卫星公司
are which stood on them stood on on them
站在他们身上的是站在他们身上的
sell on their own buy them by themselves
自行出售自行购买
before but now a part of the Alibaba
以前但现在是阿里巴巴的一部分
sort of family and the the arrange the
某种家庭和安排
things that these companies do is pretty
这些公司做的事情很漂亮
diverse Ali pay is like PayPal except
多样化的Ali支付类似于PayPal，但
unlike PayPal you can use a leap a
与PayPal不同，您可以使用
everywhere it is everywhere you can go
随处可见，随处可见
to a little village you go a little
你去一个小村庄
little hole-in-the-wall restaurant in
在的小墙上的餐厅
the village in China and you can use
中国的村庄，您可以使用
your phone to pay for the meal right
您的手机支付餐费
imagine being able to go you know go do
想象能够去，你知道去做
that in a place where they they don't
在他们不喜欢的地方
otherwise have a cash register they'll
否则要有收银机
still take paypal it just doesn't happen
仍然需要贝宝，只是没有发生
right
对
Ali pay is accepted in a lot of places
阿里支付在很多地方都可以接受
in the West right because the Chinese of
在西方，因为中国的
course are burgeoning for us and there's
当然对我们来说正在蓬勃发展，
a lot of economy-related so le pays a
很多与经济有关的事情，所以乐付了
leap a ubiquitous unlike anything else
飞跃无处不在
it's it's more bigger than anything I've
它比我拥有的任何东西都更大
seen certain in all my travels and I've
在我的所有旅行中看到确定的东西，我已经
been talking about Alibaba in their use
一直在谈论阿里巴巴的使用
cases for spring for a long time so you
Spring 盒很久了，所以你
might recall that a few years ago I did
可能回想起几年前
this spring at China scale right this is
今年春天在中国这样的规模是
a blog from 2013 when I spent three
我花了三个时间从2013年开始写博客
months in in in Shanghai which is a an
在上海的一个月
hour's plane ride from Hangzhou where
从杭州哪里坐飞机一个小时
Alibaba are located and you know I
阿里巴巴位于，你知道我
talked about their use
谈到他们的用途
then Alibaba and team all and so on and
然后阿里巴巴和所有团队等等
the thing that I think most people might
我认为大多数人可能会做的事情
appreciate about Alibaba these days is
这些天对阿里巴巴的赞赏是
when they hear about 11:11 so every
当他们听到11:11的时候
November 11th and we're fast
11月11日，我们很快
nearing that so you know obviously hug
接近那个所以你显然知道拥抱
ops to all my friends at Alibaba 11:11
在阿里巴巴向我所有的朋友致敬11:11
is November 11th it's singles day or
是11月11日是光棍节，还是
double Styx day and it's a day where
斯蒂克斯（Styx）双重天气，这是一天
they routinely routinely in a single
他们通常一次例行
24-hour period you know blow out any
您知道24小时内会发生什么
sales record you might have heard of so
您可能听说过的销售记录
in 2012 that record was three billion
在2012年，这个记录是30亿
dollars in a single 24-hour period now
现在只需24小时即可获得美元
that was a solid at least six years ago
至少在6年​​前是可靠的
so Alibaba 11:11 2017 sales let's see
所以阿里巴巴11:11 2017的销售让我们看看
what that was right
那是对的
TechCrunch Oh 25 billion in a single 21
一个21亿250亿哦
where do they go hey come back 25
他们去哪里了嘿回来25
billion in a single 25.1 25 billion in a
单个25.1亿中的25亿
single 24-hour period
24小时单身
the reason the money isn't so
钱不是那么的原因
interesting as this scale right
有趣的是，这个比例合适
the scale is which interesting and per
规模是有趣的
this article that I wrote you know years
我写的这篇文章你知道几年了
ago why is this for this article that I
以前为什么这是我的这篇文章
wrote years ago top team on Taobao you
多年前写在淘宝上的顶尖团队
know 147 million user visits purchases
知道有1.47亿用户访问
of 30 million people and nearly a
三千万人
hundred million paid orders at midnight
午夜一亿份已付订单
more than 10 million users were
超过1000万用户
currently concurrently online
目前同时在线
transacting doing sales right this is
交易做销售权这是
this isn't just people reading data this
这不只是人们在读数据
is actually committing data to stores
实际上是将数据提交到存储
and creating small little contacts with
并与
a company right that's incredible I mean
我认为这是令人难以置信的公司权利
that these kinds of numbers just aren't
这些数字不是
what most people are think over you know
大多数人对您的想法知道
I think most people are not aware of
我认为大多数人都不知道
this kind of numbers that was six years
这样的数字是六年
ago
前
the numbers are even more insane now
现在的数字更加疯狂
obviously and so Alibaba has become kind
显然，因此阿里巴巴变得友善
of interesting now the thing about China
有趣的是关于中国的事情
and Mike my humble experience is that
和迈克，我卑微的经历是
there is an incredibly vibrant
有一个令人难以置信的活力
open-source ecosystem within but it's
内含开源生态系统
for a couple of reasons it's sort of a
由于几个原因，它有点像
pake to those of us in the West that
向我们西方的人开放
don't read Chinese and so it it's always
不读中文，所以它总是
been useful for me as an exercise to go
对我来说是一项有用的运动
there I I speak every year I spend time
我每年花时间在那里说话
with organizations there who are using
与那里正在使用的组织
spring and of course Alibaba and Baidu
春天，当然还有阿里巴巴和百度
and you you and all these intense and
而你和所有这些激烈的
all these large organizations that you
所有这些大型组织
know dominate the Internet in the East
知道在东方统治互联网
and certainly dominate in general
并且肯定在总体上占主导地位
they're among the largest and webs in
他们是最大的网站之一
the world if not the largest they are
如果不是最大的世界
using spring and Tao Alibaba is in a
用春天，陶阿里巴巴在
good example every organization that I
我每个组织的好榜样
can think of in Alibaba is using spring
可以想到在阿里巴巴正在使用春天
and they've been using spring forever in
他们一直在使用spring
some cases there were gaps in the things
在某些情况下，事物之间存在差距
that spring could support or address and
春天可以支持或解决
the Alibaba engineering groups would
阿里巴巴工程团队会
fill those gaps and build on top of it
填补这些空白并在此基础上建立
but they they chose to build in spring
但是他们选择在春天建造
because what else are gonna use right
因为还有什么要用的
you're
你是
it's it's 2005 you want to build
是要建造的2005年
something at scale what's the
大规模的东西是什么
alternative
另类
right spring is that's all you got so
正确的春天就是你所拥有的
they took it they built on the spring
他们把它建在春天
and they plugged in some gaps for things
他们填补了一些空白
like service registration and discovery
如服务注册和发现
and building services and they even have
和建筑服务，甚至
frameworks that emerged internally and
内部出现的框架
um a lot of these different
很多这些不同
organizations started you know
组织开始你知道
contemporaneously they started at the
同时，他们开始于
same time solving the same problem
同时解决同一问题
independent of each other and they all
彼此独立，他们都
arrived at spring plus some you know
到达春天加上一些你知道的
some seasonings if you will so they is
一些调味料，如果你愿意的话
they've got different solutions
他们有不同的解决方案
sometimes in this within the same large
有时在这个范围之内
massive organization and one of them is
庞大的组织，其中之一是
double and I hope to be able to revisit
加倍，我希望能够重访
the topic of double in a another video
另一个视频中的双重话题
actually that's actually I will
其实那是我会的
definitely it's it's on the list right
肯定是在清单上
it's one of the things I wanted to cover
这是我想讲的一件事
in this video but it's just so massive a
在这个视频中，但它是如此庞大
discussion that it's worth revisiting
值得回顾的讨论
but suffice it to say double now built
但是只要说现在已经建立了两倍就足够了
on spring boot and spring cloud right so
在 spring boot 和Spring 云上，所以
double is even more interesting today my
双倍今天更有趣
friends we're gonna focus we're gonna
我们要关注的朋友
confine ourselves to spring cloud
局限于Spring Cloud
alibaba so you may know that we have
阿里巴巴，所以您可能知道我们有
integrations with the different cloud
与不同云的集成
players and with different you know
玩家和不同的你知道
spring you know with cloudy sort of
你知道的春天，多云
infrastructure spring cloud has in the
Spring Cloud拥有的基础架构
incubator we have a spring cloud alibaba
孵化器我们有一个阿里巴巴的春天云
spring cloud Azur spring cloud AWS
春季云Azur春季云AWS
spring cloud TCP and I've done videos on
Spring Cloud TCP，我已经完成了视频
these right so today we're gonna look at
这些正确的，所以今天我们要看看
spring cloud Alibaba now spring cloud
春天的云阿里巴巴现在春天的云
Alibaba is actually - it's it's
阿里巴巴实际上是-是的
two-tiered so if you look at spring
两层，所以如果你看看春天
cloud GCP for example sprinklers GCP
云GCP，例如洒水器GCP
serves GCP Google cloud platform and
服务GCP Google云平台，以及
there is nothing really of use in spring
春天没有什么用
cloud GCP if you're not planning and
如果您不打算使用云GCP，
using Google cloud right that that makes
使用Google Cloud的权利
sense
感
Alibaba under the hand have a really
手中的阿里巴巴真有
good open source footprint there's a lot
好的开源足迹有很多
of good stuff you can use that requires
可以使用的好东西需要
absolutely nothing of their platform you
绝对没有他们平台的
don't have to use it you can just run it
不必使用它就可以运行它
in your local machine and it works just
在您的本地计算机上，它只适用于
fine and the spring cloud integration
精与Spring Cloud整合
connects us to those things now we're
现在将我们与这些事物联系起来
gonna talk about
要谈论
knockos and sentinel today one thing
今天的kickos和sentinel一件事
that we're not gonna talk about today
我们今天不谈论
because it's just not quite there is
因为它不完全是
Apache rocket MQ and rocket MQ
Apache火箭MQ和火箭MQ
is the open-source messaging platform
是开源消息传递平台
that Alibaba built up years ago right
是阿里巴巴几年前建立的
this serves their use cases it still
这仍然为他们的用例服务
serves their scale on their use cases
在用例上扩大规模
and it does does so add you know you
这样做确实增加了您的认识
know forget about web-scale
知道忘记网络规模
china scale right this is actually a
中国规模，这实际上是一个
project that I think we would be ranged
我认为我们会被放养的项目
it would be very interesting to look at
看看会很有趣
and so there is as I understand it now
因此，据我所知
work being done to make this a better
为了使这个更好而正在做的工作
supported citizen of the spring cloud
支持的Spring Cloud公民
Alibaba project and you know in that
阿里巴巴项目，您知道
vein to provide spring integration and
提供Spring 整合的静脉和
spring cloud stream bindings and and so
Spring Cloud Stream 绑定等等
on but in the meantime we will focus on
继续，但与此同时，我们将专注于
these things that we can use today
这些我们今天可以使用的东西
namely send Sentinel and knockos and
即发送Sentinel和Kickos，
then we'll look at spring cloud a Leonor
那么我们来看一下莱昂诺尔的Spring Cloud
Ali cloud right this is the cloud
阿里云对了这就是云
platform and you'll see that it's just
平台，您会看到它只是
does with the other spring cloud cloud
与另一个春天的云
you know integrations trivial to take
你知道整合很简单
your spring application to the cloud to
您的春季应用程序到云
take advantage of services running in
利用运行中的服务
those cloud platforms and so my service
那些云平台，所以我的服务
is my application you know I'm gonna run
是我的应用程序，你知道我要运行
everything in my local machine I am a
我本地机器上的所有东西
anybody who knows me knows that I'm a
任何认识我的人都知道我
strident believer in using the simplest
坚定的信徒使用最简单的方法
thing that can possibly work to run my
可能可以运行我的东西
applications today I don't want to I
今天我不想的应用程序
don't want to have to deal with a wall
不想面对一堵墙
of Yama files so I tend to use something
的Yama文件，所以我倾向于使用一些东西
like Cloud Foundry cloud fund it just
就像Cloud Foundry云基金一样
lets me give it a jar I can run it and
让我给它一个罐子，我可以运行它，
then on top of that I run whatever one
然后最重要的是
so you can run Cloud Foundry anyway
因此您仍然可以运行Cloud Foundry
right but there are certain services in
是的，但是里面有某些服务
different regions of the world in
世界不同地区
different clouds that are compelling and
引人入胜的不同云
so for example if you're in Asia in
例如，如果您在亚洲
China in particular two very popular
中国特别是两个很受欢迎
options are Microsoft Microsoft's got a
选项是微软微软有
sort of white label Azur thing that
那种白色标签Azur的东西
isn't quite azure but it's managed by a
不是很蔚蓝，但是由
local Chinese partner for four reasons
中国本地合作伙伴有四个原因
and that's compelling its most of
这引人注目
Microsoft Azure but in in China right
Microsoft Azure但在中国
which is it can be very very valuable if
如果这是非常非常有价值的
you're trying to get into that market
您正在尝试进入那个市场
and then of course there's Ali cloud
然后当然有阿里云
right and so we're gonna focus on Ali
对的，所以我们将专注于阿里
cloud today let's build a new
今天的云，让我们建立一个新的
application a regular Springwood
申请常规的斯普林伍德
application
应用
called bootiful Alibaba we're going to
被称为可战利品的阿里巴巴，我们将
use the web support when use Lombok when
使用Lombok时使用网络支持
use the the cloud starter right I want
使用我想要的云启动器
the starter not because I want to lose a
首发不是因为我想失去一个
cloud bootstrap there we go we don't
云引导我们走了，我们不走
want anything from spring cloud part per
想要每个春天的云部分
se except for the dependency management
除了依赖管理
and the the basic core common
和基本的共同点
dependencies okay we'll have to at the
依赖关系好吧，我们将不得不
moment we'll have to add the check boxes
现在我们必须添加复选框
for Alibaba manually at the moment we've
现在我们手动为阿里巴巴服务
already got you know we've got support
已经知道您已经获得支持
for eight of us four pivotal Cloud
对于我们四个中的八个关键云
Foundry for GCP for Microsoft Azure and
适用于Microsoft Azure和GCP的Foundry
and so on so we've got the you know the
依此类推，所以我们知道了
big four they're already in Alibaba I
他们已经在阿里巴巴大四
hope is going to join the release train
希望将加入发布火车
in 2019 so here we go we've got this
在2019年，所以我们开始吧
this very simple application I'm gonna
这个非常简单的应用程序
use all the all the basics it doesn't
使用所有它没有的基础知识
really matter we'll hit generate and in
真的很重要，我们会点击生成和
my downloads directory you see I've got
我的下载目录，您将看到
this file I'll open that up in my IDE
我将在IDE中打开该文件
and the first thing that we're gonna do
这是我们要做的第一件事
is we're gonna add the dependencies that
是我们要添加依赖项
we need to be able to work with spring
我们需要能够与春季合作
cloud Alibaba okay we just get that out
云阿里巴巴好吧，我们把它弄出来
of the way right now normally this would
现在通常情况下
have been done by the time I launched by
在我启动时已经完成了
IDE cuz we would have had check boxes
IDE Cuz，我们本来会有复选框
but again as I say those just aren't
但是正如我所说的那样，
there quite yet and that's for better
在那里，那是为了更好
force this is a good opportunity for
强制这是一个很好的机会
those of you who are just trying to
那些只是想
stuff out if you want to feedback if you
如果你想反馈的话
want to you know let us SAP you know let
想知道您让我们联系SAP您知道让我们
us know how you feel sand off please
我们知道您的心情如何
go to github.com spring cloud incubator
转到github.com春季云孵化器
and then you'll see spring cloud Alibaba
然后你会看到春天的云阿里巴巴
and there we are all the more interested
而且我们更加感兴趣
in your feedback please so here we go
在您的反馈中，请继续
let's add a few dependencies the first
让我们先添加一些依赖
of which is going to be our maven Bill
其中将是我们的行家比尔
of Materials dependency so I'll just
的材料依赖关系，所以我就
copy and paste this and we've got the
复制并粘贴这个，我们已经
bits that we we don't need from this so
我们不需要的一点，所以
Alibaba will say spring cloud
阿里巴巴会说Spring Cloud
I'll leave Bob dependencies and we want
我将留下鲍勃的依赖关系，我们想要
a version
厌恶
Oh point 2.0 release all right
哦点2.0发布好了
yeah okay so there's that now once we
是的，所以一旦我们
add this we're going to add some
添加这个，我们要添加一些
dependencies here so let's see these
这里的依赖项，让我们看看这些
will be OSS you know
你知道的将会是OSS
let's see a let's see a see okay so here
让我们来看看，让我们来看看
dependency spring
依赖Spring
cloud
云
cloud and then we want spring cloud
云，然后我们要春天云
Alibaba what the entities for knockos
阿里巴巴的实体为什么
configuration config and the version
配置配置和版本
certainly the whole point of adding at
当然，整个添加点
that Bill of Materials maven
那个物料清单专家
dependencies to avoid just that
避免这种依赖
requirement so not close discovery and
需求，所以不要关闭发现和
we want Sentinel right
我们想要哨兵正确
and finally early cloud OSs
最后是早期的云操作系统
okay
好的
alright so here we go we've got a number
好了，所以在这里，我们有一个数字
of different dependencies in there OSs
有不同的依赖关系
stands for object storage system okay so
代表对象存储系统好吧
we'll come back to that all in a bit
我们稍后会回到所有这些
actually for now since we don't need
实际上，因为我们不需要
that yet we don't have it configured
但是我们没有配置它
when it comment out that that stuff
当它把那个东西注释掉时
right now I think we might just calm
现在我想我们可能会冷静
down all of it and just see what we can
记下来，看看我们能做什么
gradually reintroduce all right so now
逐渐重新介绍好吧，所以现在
those dependencies I've added those
这些依赖关系我已经添加了那些
dependencies I've added those
依赖我添加了那些
dependencies and they work reliably over
依赖关系，它们可靠地工作
maven central that said if you're in a
Maven Central说如果您在
region of the world where maven central
Maven中央的世界区域
isn't as fast as you'd like it during a
速度不如您所愿
region where you might be using a leak
您可能正在使用泄漏的区域
cloud and access to public repositories
云和对公共存储库的访问
like maven central is slower than
像Maven Central慢于
perhaps you'd like it you might you
也许你想要它，也许你
might use your own custom settings that
可能会使用您自己的自定义设置
XML file ok so I you would put the
好的XML文件，所以我将
Settings XML file in your main m2
主m2中的设置XML文件
repository and the URL that you would
存储库和您将要使用的URL
use I'll let you configure out the
使用，我会让您配置
rescue you have to make this a mirror of
营救你必须使它成为镜子
your central you just say mirror of and
您的中央，您只需说出
then central and the URL from alibaba's
然后是中心，还有阿里巴巴的网址
maven repository is the following
Maven存储库如下
okay there we go so that's that URL if
好的，我们去了，那就是该网址，如果
you if you created maven if you create a
如果您创建了maven，则创建了一个
setting stuff XML and then making a
设置资料XML，然后进行
mirror of this one HTTP maven Ali you
这一个HTTP Maven Ali的镜像
calm for / Nexus for set content for /
对Nexus感到安心
groups for such public you'll you'll get
这样的公众团体，你会得到
a fast connection could be useful you
快速连接可能对您有用
know but like I said maybe in central
知道，但是就像我说的那样，也许在中央
works fine for me where I sit right now
我现在坐在那里对我来说很好
and in Singapore for example so very
例如在新加坡
good now we have an application I'm
好，现在我们有一个应用程序
gonna build an application and our
要建立一个应用程序，我们
application is going to we're gonna take
应用程序将要我们去
advantage first of centinall now
现在先获得centinall的优势
sentinel is a thing that grew out of Ali
哨兵是阿里长大的东西
Baba's insane scale requirements right I
爸爸疯狂的规模要求我
told you those numbers before as you can
尽你所能告诉你这些数字
imagine having the ability to centrally
想象有能力集中
configure and and protect services is
配置和保护服务是
invaluable and Sentinel is the engine of
无价之宝，而Sentinel是
that protection central keeps watch over
保护中心一直在监视
flows of data into services and limits
数据流向服务和限制
it it can throttle it it can do flow
它可以节流它可以流
control rules it can do all sorts of
控制规则，它可以做各种
interesting things I have downloaded
我下载的有趣的东西
Sentinel and sensor you can download
您可以下载前哨和传感器
sentinels well by the way github calm
哨兵很好地github平静
wellactually github.com Alibaba send to
很好github.com阿里巴巴发送给
know okay and when you go here you'll
知道好吧，当你去这里时，你会
see the releases directory or item and
查看发布目录或项目，以及
there you'll be given to downloads since
在那里，您将获得下载，因为
on dashboard one-30 en that's the
在仪表板One-30上，这是
English you know internationalized
你知道国际化的英语
version of the central project and
中央项目的版本和
here's the regular sort of by default
这是默认情况下的常规类型
Chinese multiple Dianetics multiple sort
中文多重Dianetics多重排序
of encoding this but Chinese language
编码，但是中文
sense um dashboard now you'll see that
感觉到仪表板，现在您会看到
the English one is not quite perfect yet
英语还不是很完美
they're changing I mean literally
他们正在改变，我的意思是说
they're making they're fixing things
他们正在修整东西
every day all the time they're very
每天无时无刻不在
responsive this release came out 10 days
响应此版本发布了10天
ago and so the English one you know it's
以前，所以你知道的英语是
not that the translations aren't great
不是说翻译不是很好
it's that some buttons just haven't been
只是有些按钮没有被使用
translated yet right and so that's
翻译得还不错，所以
that's just if you see it I've already
就像您看到的那样，我已经
filed a few issues no there
提出了一些没有的问题
fixing it as fast as as they can and
尽快修复它，并
they're doing a great job so I'm always
他们做得很好，所以我总是
grateful for that okay so you can
对此表示感谢，因此您可以
download that get it going on your local
下载，让它在您本地播放
machine and the way I'm gonna start it
机器以及我要启动的方式
up this I'm gonna run this little script
我要运行这个小脚本
I wrote called you know and just says
我写了一个叫你知道，只是说
set the server port to a t-888 moment
将服务器端口设置为t-888
spring good app of course so Java - jar
当然是春季的好应用，所以Java-jar
since from dashboard I set it to a t-888
因为从仪表板我将其设置为t-888
because 8888 is you know 883 apes and
因为8888是883猿吗
points are good look right I figured why
点好看我知道为什么
not it's a good luck number in China so
不是中国的好运气
there we go we'll hit run let's see what
我们去那里，我们将运行，让我们看看
we got there we go so it's up and
我们到了那里，所以去了，
running on port 88 88 we can go here
在88 88端口上运行我们可以在这里
localhost all right I'm gonna go there
本地主机好吧，我要去那里
we can see there's nothing registered an
我们可以看到没有注册任何东西
application yet nothing to to manage yet
应用程序尚未管理
so we really need to build an
所以我们真的需要建立一个
application that will that we can then
我们将可以使用的应用程序
connect to this and in order to do that
连接到这个，为了做到这一点
we need to in our code configure our
我们需要在我们的代码中配置我们的
connection to central ok so the way you
连接到中央就可以了
do that is you set the dashboard
就是您设置仪表板
location so application up properties
位置，因此应用程序的属性
Sentinel since you know I'll guess we
前哨，因为你知道我会猜我们
need to add in the dependencies Urmi
需要添加依赖项Urmi
already dashboard dashboard dashboard
仪表板已经仪表板
okay so we'll just say localhost:8080
好吧，我们只说localhost：8080
there you go um and you could also put
你去那里，你也可以放
this stuff I'm gonna put a lot of stuff
我要放很多东西
in bootstrap that properties which you
在引导中，您可以
know viewers will know is the place
知道观众会知道的地方
where spring cloud looks for things that
春天的云在寻找什么
are then used to resolve things needed
然后用来解决需要的事情
in the bootstrap process of spring cloud
在春天云的引导过程中
itself so for things like service
本身，例如服务
registration and discovery etc
注册和发现等
configuration values these things that
配置重视这些东西
are then used to resolve the rest of the
然后用于解决其余的
configuration for example so I'm gonna
例如配置，我要
put as much as I can here I'm not not
我在这里尽我所能
sure strictly speaking whether this
严格来说，这是否
needs to be there or not but why not
需要在那里还是为什么不
right and I'm gonna give this a name
对的，我要给它起个名字
it's gonna be called beautiful Alibaba
它会被称为美丽的阿里巴巴
all right there we go there's my my
好吧，我们去那里是我的
application Sentinel okay and there's
应用程序Sentinel好的，还有
our configuration name and now in our
我们的配置名称，现在在
application we're going to create an
我们将要创建一个应用程序
endpoint that will then use Sentinel to
然后将使用Sentinel的端点
protect so let's use Sentinel first
保护，让我们先使用Sentinel
first let's create an in point that we
首先让我们创建一个切入点
can protect in code actually we're gonna
可以保护代码，实际上我们要
try this a couple of different ways
尝试几种不同的方法
we're going to configure a simple rest
我们将配置一个简单的休息
controller so um readings rest
控制器，使读数保持静止
controller alright get mapping I'm gonna
控制器好了，我要映射
we're gonna configure the protection for
我们将为
this endpoint in code so I'll call it
这个端点在代码中，所以我称它为
code and you know what we're gonna time
代码，你知道我们要做什么
for a little bit of Chinese we're gonna
为了一点中文，我们要
say normally how that's a Shanghainese
通常说那是上海话
it's it's Mandarin basically but it's
基本上是普通话，但是
slightly different dialect for hello and
方言与hello和略有不同
then we'll do one for the dashboard and
然后我们为仪表板做一个
we'll look at that in a second and we'll
我们待会儿再看
protect this one with the dashboard in a
使用仪表板保护
second dashboard
第二个仪表板
and there will say yeah that's more
而且还会说是的
mainstream sort of meandering okay okay
主流曲折好吧好吧
so we've got now arrest endpoint now by
所以我们现在已经逮捕了终点
default everything in your application
默认应用程序中的所有内容
is protected if you're using sentinel
如果您使用哨兵，则受到保护
okay so we have a web application is
好的，所以我们有一个Web应用程序是
protected already these resources
已经保护了这些资源
correspond to endpoints that sintel is
对应于sintel是
aware if we haven't configured in rules
知道我们是否没有规则配置
for them but that doesn't mean that
对他们来说，但这并不意味着
since almost not aware of them we can
因为几乎不了解他们，所以我们可以
configure rules manually in code so
在代码中手动配置规则，以便
let's do that here we can say Sentinel
让我们在这里做，我们可以说哨兵
code configuration and create a beam
代码配置并创建梁
that gets invoked when the application
当应用程序被调用时
is up and running it's initializing it
启动并运行它正在对其进行初始化
so I'll do public void configure sand
所以我会做公共无效的配置沙子
tunnel throws exception all right
隧道抛出异常可以了
and we'll do at configuration and here
我们将在这里进行配置
we're gonna write some code you're gonna
我们要写一些代码
save flow rule that far equals new flow
保存远等于新流量的流量规则
rule and what we want to do is run a
规则，我们要做的是
create a rule that will protect our
建立一条规则来保护我们的
resource and their resources as I say
我说的资源及其资源
code and the rule will have we know
代码和规则将使我们知道
allow I need to be able to overwhelm
允许我需要不知所措
this endpoint with my browser so I'm
这个端点与我的浏览器，所以我
gonna load I'm gonna set it to a
要加载，我将其设置为
nonsensically ridiculously low number
荒谬的低数字
like two okay but obviously in a real
像两个还可以，但显然是真实的
production system one would hope that
生产系统希望
you'd handle a good deal more than that
你会做得更多
I always said it to someone whenever I
我总是跟别人说
do a spring Club gateway and the circuit
做一个Spring 俱乐部网关和电路
breaker I'm sorry the rate limiter I
断路器，对不起限速器，我
also show like five per second or
也每秒显示五次
something like that so you know this is
这样的事情，所以你知道这是
just problems of doing demos I suppose
我想做演示的问题
and then set the grade and the grade is
然后设置等级，等级是
the thing that we're gonna use to
我们会习惯的事情
determine what triggers the protection
确定触发保护的因素
right so that flow grade QPS so that's
对，所以流量等级QPS是
queries per second okay and then we want
每秒查询没问题，然后我们要
to say I want to limit the different
说我想限制不同
this Apple basically that's just the
这个苹果基本上就是
best age I'm not sure I have to specify
我不确定我必须指定的最佳年龄
that and then finally I'll say flow rule
然后我会说流规则
manager dot load rules collections dot
经理点加载规则集合点
singleton list fr
单例列表fr
all right there's my simple rule okay so
好吧，这是我的简单规则，所以
there's my simple rule all we've done
我已经完成了一条简单的规则
thus far as explicitly protect code so
到目前为止，明确保护代码
let's see what happens if we start this
让我们看看如果开始这个会发生什么
application up right now
现在申请
okay it's up and running localhost:8080
好的，它已经启动并正在运行localhost：8080
forward slash code so if I there you go
正斜杠代码，如果我在那里你去
if I overwhelm it it says there's known
如果我不知所措，它说有一个已知的
how how but now if I will and the
如何但现在如果我愿意和
keyboard a bit here there we go it says
键盘有点在这里，我们去说
blocked by Sentinel flow limiting okay
被Sentinel流量限制阻止了
so that means that we got the default
所以这意味着我们得到了默认
white label sort of protection rejection
白标防护等级
endpoint thing that's a little boring oh
终结点的东西有点无聊哦
yeah you know we might want to have a
是的，你知道我们可能想要一个
little bit more control over that and we
多一点控制，我们
can certainly do that one way to do that
当然可以做到这一点的一种方法
is to use a a property you could say at
是要使用您可以在
get mapping error
获取映射错误
okay screen you do response entity okay
好的屏幕，您可以响应实体吗
response error and but wouldn't what
响应错误，但不会
we're gonna just want to say response
我们只想说回应
entity dot you know too many status
您知道状态太多的实体点
issue D status too many requests dot
问题D状态太多，要求点
content type is what I want what do we
内容类型就是我想要的
want this to be we want it to be media
希望这成为我们希望成为媒体
type application Jason died are you
类型应用Jason死了吗
dodging content body will be a body
躲避内容的身体将是一个身体
collection stop singleton map error
收集停止单例地图错误
wouldn't take it anymore
不会再忍受了
okay and then send it back so those are
好，然后再寄回去
our error endpoint let's see what that
我们的错误端点让我们看看
word if that works in order Festa
单词，如果这是为了节日
it's cancellous i need to configure that
这是我需要配置的
to be the input so we do that by going
成为输入，所以我们通过
to our properties of course and
当然是我们的财产
specifying the block page so what's
指定阻止页面，这是什么
happening is that when we call this
发生的是，当我们称之为
endpoint too many times it's gonna send
端点发送的次数过多
it to send the user to that block page
它将用户发送到该阻止页面
I'm gonna send them there now you could
我现在要把它们送到那里
by the way this is all being done
顺便说一下，这一切都完成了
through aspect oriented programming an
通过面向切面的编程
AOP and you know integrations with
AOP，您知道与
spring filters and all the right things
Spring 过滤器和所有正确的东西
right the spring the integration here is
春天，这里的整合就是
seamless for spring developers but
对于春季开发人员来说是无缝的，但是
behind the scenes underneath the hood
引擎盖下的幕后
central is just of course an API and
中央当然是一个API，
that's well first of all let's see this
很好，首先让我们看看
working right status equals 999 what did
工作权状态等于999
i do there no explicit mapping for error
我没有错误的显式映射
content well I feel like that could have
内容很好，我觉得那可能有
gone better
变得更好
code let's see maybe this could be maybe
代码让我们看看也许这可能是
I assumed too much string all right try
我认为字符串太多可以尝试
that again application yeah it is
再次申请是的，他妈的
equal to error
等于错误
no explicit blockage
无明显阻塞
this should be
这应该是
am i doing something very wrong here
我在这里做错什么吗
let's see HTTP localhost:8080 for such
让我们来看看HTTP localhost：8080
error I feel like that should be obvious
错误，我觉得应该很明显
get mapping error right looks okay to me
正确获取映射错误对我来说还可以
that is so weird it's saying no explicit
太奇怪了，说没有明确
endpoint for error well
错误的终点
walk
步行
same thing
一样
does that be a post I mean what's the
那是职位吗，我的意思是
deal here request mapping
在这里处理请求映射
that should be that I would swear that
那应该是我发誓
has worked before but you know what do I
曾经工作过，但是你知道我该怎么办
know
知道
so spring cloud starter great we got
所以春季云启动器很棒，我们得到了
that spring good start test Sentinel ah
那年春天好开始考前哨啊
well that looks like an issue doesn't it
好吧，看起来像不是一个问题
my friends we are dealing with something
我的朋友，我们正在处理一些事情
here that I don't understand uh let's
在这里我不明白，让我们
just try something simple like ich cuz I
只是尝试一些简单的像ich cuz I
feel ok get mapping I know I've seen
我知道我已经看到映射了，感觉还可以
this before and eek
之前和之后
it occurs me that might be interfering
发生我可能会干扰
with the generic spring boot sort of
带有通用的 spring boot
white navel page code there there we go
白色肚脐页面代码在那里
so that that that was right so now I
所以那是正确的，所以现在我
guess error is the issue that the spring
猜错是春天的问题
boot error page got in the way base
启动错误页面妨碍了基础
closed interfering so let's try this
封闭干扰，让我们尝试一下
again now response entity return
现在再次响应实体返回
response entity dot status HTTP status
响应实体点状态HTTP状态
that too many requests dot
点太多
content type equals media type
内容类型等于媒体类型
application adjacent value and then body
应用程序相邻值然后是主体
is going to be a single object that will
将成为一个单一的对象，
turn into a jason structured error can't
变成jason结构错误
take it anymore okay there we are that's
好了，我们就在那里
our our build and we can try this again
我们的构建，我们可以再试一次
/e k--
/ e k--
okay so we go here whoops
好吧，我们去这里哦
localhost code okay there so there's my
本地代码好了，所以有我的
application Jason utf-8 rate value so
应用Jason utf-8速率值
you can do whatever you want to do there
你可以在那里做任何你想做的事
right you have full control this is one
对，你有完全的控制权，这是一个
way to do it is you in for want to
要做的方法就是你想要
handle like this another is if one or
这样处理另一个是如果一个或
more generic sort of object-oriented
更通用的面向对象
thing a callback interface there's a
回调接口的东西
thing called a flow what is it called a
所谓的流是什么
URL block handler so let's do that we've
URL阻止处理程序，让我们开始吧
got a custom URL block hander handler
有一个自定义URL块处理程序处理程序
URL block handler implements URL block
URL块处理程序实现URL块
handler implement these methods and you
处理程序实现这些方法，您
know we're just gonna log I guess the
知道我们只是要登录，我猜
information here I quite prefer that
这里的信息我比较喜欢
first math mechanism but this might be
第一个数学机制，但这可能是
more interesting to you and that's why I
对您来说更有趣，这就是为什么我
show it to you so it's just a regular
给你看，所以这只是一个常规
spring bean you don't even have to do
甚至不需要做的四季 bean
anything else to make it to make spring
还有其他办法可以使春天
and since we're all aware of it so
既然我们都知道
here's the request this ants and de okay
这是蚂蚁的要求，还可以
and what we're gonna do is we're gonna
而我们要做的是
get access to the response are yes dot
访问响应是点
get the writer and we're gonna send a
得到作家，我们将发送一个
crying emoji okay and that's it that's
哭泣的表情符号好吧，就是这样
my boring is all all get out you will
我很无聊都滚蛋
block handler custom URL block Hendra
块处理程序自定义URL块Hendra
bean
bean 角，扁 bean
all right now take two there we go so
现在就带两个去吧
what if I if I if I tripped that when I
如果我摔倒了怎么办
get this information as well okay so
得到这些信息还好，所以
that's one way to do it is to use code
那是做到这一点的一种方法是使用代码
like I've done here to use code and then
就像我在这里使用代码，然后
and two and so on you can also configure
和两个等等，您还可以配置
these flow rules using the Sentinel
使用Sentinel的这些流规则
dashboard itself now the Sentinel
仪表板本身现在是Sentinel
dashboard doesn't persist that
仪表板不能持久
information unless you NSU ask it to and
信息，除非您向NSU询问并
there's a way to do it and I'll allude
有办法做到，我会暗示
to it in a bit but it doesn't have any
有点，但它没有任何
it doesn't have any state in of itself
它本身没有任何状态
and so in order for you to - you know
所以为了你-你知道
when you use it keep in mind that it'll
当您使用它时，请记住它会
it won't it won't be durable across
不会，它不会持久耐用
restarts so you have to you have to then
重新启动，所以您必须要然后
you know either persistent durably
你知道要么持久
somewhere or or just keep reconfiguring
某个地方或只是继续进行重新配置
it but for now since it's a demo and I
它，但是现在，因为它是一个演示，我
don't want to complicate things manner
不想让事情复杂化
to complicate matters too much we'll
使事情变得过于复杂，我们将
we'll just leave it as is okay okay now
我们就把它放好吧，现在好吧
so what we're gonna do we have Sentinel
所以我们要做的是哨兵
up and running and we have to we want to
启动并运行，我们必须要
configure you know we've told it to
配置您知道我们已经告诉过
configure itself so we've told it to our
配置自己，所以我们已经告诉了我们
application to register the application
申请注册申请
is now here and the only reason it's
现在在这里，唯一的原因是
here by the way if you if you run this
顺便说一句，如果你运行这个
program if you run the code and you
程序，如果您运行代码并且您
start the code up but you don't hit one
启动代码，但您没有成功
of these endpoints this won't register
在这些端点中，这不会注册
right you have to actually hit through
对，你必须真正击穿
the filter one of the endpoints that
过滤其中一个端点
sentinels protecting for Sentinel to
保护哨兵的哨兵
sort of lazily materialize the the
有点懒惰地实现了
client instance here in the dashboard so
客户端实例在仪表板中，因此
here's the instance of bootiful Ababa
这是可恶的阿巴巴的实例
I can hit monitoring there's no sort of
我可以进行监控了
interesting endpoint there here's my
有趣的终点，这是我的
resource change
资源变化
I saw if I go here you know we don't
我看到如果我去这里，你知道我们不会
really get much out of this at the
真的从中得到很多
moment if I go here I can see that we
如果我去这里的那一刻，我可以看到我们
have a code endpoint right and I want to
有一个正确的代码端点，我想
also see the dashboard in point
也可以查看仪表板
and right now there's no rules you can
现在没有规则可以
see it just says anyhow right no
看到它只是说反正不
problems there so now go back here and
问题在那里，所以现在回到这里，
as soon as I do that you can see it says
当我这样做时，您会看到它说
dashboard right and if I click on this
仪表板右侧，如果我单击此
now something code and fav icon and
现在一些代码和收藏夹图标和
dashboard both have their graphs so it
仪表板都有他们的图，所以
takes a little bit there they're a
需要一点点，他们是
little sort of asynchronous aren't they
有点异步不是吗
so we have the timestamp we have the
所以我们有时间戳
past queries per second and the blocked
每秒过去的查询和被阻止
queries per second right showing me how
每秒的查询量向我展示了如何
much you know has gotten through and not
你知道的很多已经过去了
gone through and I can you know very
经历了，我可以知道吗
very nice fast reactive graphs showing
非常好的快速反应图显示
me everything it's that's that's a fit
我所有的一切都是合适的
to print so to speak the user interface
可以说可以打印用户界面
it's pretty slick I'm it's fast but
它很光滑，我很快，但是
obviously I had to you know when when
显然我必须知道你什么时候
when I've what I've understood is that
当我了解到的是
this you know at any given time there
您在任何给定时间都知道
could be thousands of nodes in this
在这可能是数千个节点
graph in this tool so you have you know
该工具中的图形，以便您知道
the ability to search for nodes search
搜索节点搜索的能力
for services and then get the details
获取服务，然后获取详细信息
there what I want to do is I want to
我想做的就是
configure so you can see there's a lot
配置，所以您可以看到很多
of different rules here I can see I've
在这里我可以看到不同的规则
got a node here running this version of
这里有一个节点正在运行此版本的
Sentinel the status of the application
前哨应用程序的状态
is healthy here's the IP address it's on
是健康的，这是它所在的IP地址
my local machine here's the heartbeat
我的本地机器是心跳
time stamp the last one for this
为此最后一个时间戳
particular node you can see all that you
您可以看到特定的节点
can see the resource right you can see
可以看到正确的资源
this is a hierarchical tree like via
这是一个像via这样的层次树
where you can do a list view as well and
您还可以在其中执行列表视图
what I want to do is I want to configure
我要做的是配置
for dashboard a flow rule so I click on
仪表板的流量规则，所以我单击
the plus sign there and I'm gonna say
那里的加号，我要说
queries per second I'm gonna limit that
每秒查询数我要限制
also to two okay so keep in mind what
也要两个好，所以请记住
this is gonna do is it's gonna talk to
这是要做的是要与之交谈
our our application and set up this rule
我们的应用程序并设置此规则
but that rule will die as soon as we
但是，只要我们
restart the application so unless we
重新启动应用程序，所以除非我们
persist that somewhere okay add then
坚持在可以的地方添加然后
continue so now I've just added the flow
继续，所以现在我已经添加了流程
rule to dashboard nine uptime and so if
规则仪表板九个正常运行时间，如果
we go here now we get the same behavior
我们去这里现在我们得到相同的行为
that wasn't in place before right there
在那之前没有到位
was no flu will apply to for such
如果没有流感将适用于
dashboard before but our
仪表板之前，但我们
you know our configuration or sprinkled
你知道我们的配置还是撒了
configuration applies to either flow to
配置适用于任一流
rules configured in the dashboard or
仪表板中配置的规则或
tools configured in Java code okay and
用Java代码配置的工具还可以
so again now you get the visibility of
现在再次获得
things that you know the queries that
你知道的事情，查询
were success successful versus those
成功与那些
that were blocked you can see the
被阻止的你可以看到
information about that and all that so
有关的信息等等
that's really interesting I think I
我觉得那真的很有趣
think this is all pretty interesting
认为这都很有趣
there's a whole lot of really
真的有很多
interesting things that things that we
有趣的事情，我们的事情
could do beyond what I've shown you here
可以超越我在这里给您展示的内容
obviously but we'll have to leave it
显然，但是我们必须离开它
that I did mention that we could store
我确实提到我们可以存储
configuration for Sentinel somewhere
Sentinel的配置
some more durable well one place we
一些更耐用的地方
could store that is in knockos right
可以存储在kickos中的权利
knockos is a a naming and configuration
Kickos是一个命名和配置
server get it na naming calls
服务器得到它命名调用
configuration server right so necklace
配置服务器对吧，项链
is a naming configuration server I've
是我命名的配置服务器
got that on my local machine here here
在我这里的本地机器上得到了
we go run start and this one not cause
我们开始运行，这不是原因
by default starts up at 8848 and I was
默认情况下启动于8848
told a story by one of my friends at
我的一个朋友在讲一个故事
Alibaba that that it's 8848 because
阿里巴巴那是8848因为
apparently that's the height of Mount
显然那是Mount的高度
Everest
珠穆朗玛峰
so in meters Izzie yeah there we go
所以在米Izzie是啊，我们走了
80 48 so I think that's pretty cool
80 48所以我觉得这很酷
right that's really cool so the height
对，那真的很酷，所以高度
of a nurse is 88 48 and that's what
护士的数字是88 48
that's what the port of NACO says okay
那是NACO港口所说的
so now Coast is both a service registry
所以现在Coast既是服务注册表
as you might have understood in previous
如您先前所了解
discussions when we talked about for
我们谈论的讨论
example apache zookeeper or Hoshi Corp
例如apache zookeeper或Hoshi Corp
console or Netflix Eureka or whatever
控制台或Netflix Eureka或其他
it's also a configuration server like
这也是像
the spring cloud config server and you
Spring Cloud Config Server和您
know in the way that console or
知道该控制台或
zookeeper can be used as centralized
Zookeeper可以用作集中式
configuration servers or that Google
配置服务器或那个Google
Cloud runtime config can be used as a
云运行时配置可以用作
configuration server right
配置服务器权限
so these it plug these both plug-in into
所以这些将这两个插件都插入
the appropriate abstractions in spring
春天的适当抽象
cloud
云
for the service registration in
用于在中进行服务注册
Discovery support you use the spring
探索支持您使用Spring
cloud discovery client abstraction and
云发现客户端抽象和
it supports ribbon and plants that look
它支持丝带和看起来很漂亮的植物
bouncing and all that and for
弹跳等等
configuration well it's of course a
配置很好，当然是
property source that talks to some sort
某种形式的财产来源
of back-end right so just plugging into
后端的权利，所以只需插入
well-known SP is and you get consistency
众所周知的SP是，并且您可以获得一致性
now you can swap out your choice of
现在您可以交换选择
configuration server back-end with with
配置服务器后端与
computer you right you can do it you can
电脑，你说得对，你可以做到
go to Google cloud to config server - -
转到Google云以配置服务器--
not ghost and you know your code in Java
不是鬼，你知道你的Java代码
stays the same
保持不变
so let's see what that looks like let's
让我们来看看是什么样子
say that I wanted to participate in
说我想参加
service registration and discovery right
服务注册和发现权
I've got the dependency there this might
我那里有依赖性
be the old instance of it I'm not sure
我不确定它的旧实例
uh let's see details edit this service
嗯，让我们看看详细信息编辑此服务
okay there's an example of a thing
好，有一个例子
that's not quite yet translated but you
那还没有翻译，但是你
know we don't need to worry about it
知道我们不需要担心
anyway so there you go we've got that
无论如何，所以你去了，我们得到了
we've got the service efficient
我们的服务效率很高
discovery support and configuration so I
发现支持和配置，所以我
guess the first thing I wanna do is take
我想做的第一件事就是服用
advantage of service registration and
服务注册的优势和
discovery just to demonstrate the point
发现只是为了证明这一点
because I'm I fear that I had me I'm
因为我害怕我拥有我
that I may have lingering artifacts from
我可能有挥之不去的文物
a previous one I'm gonna switch the name
上一个我要切换名称
here I'll name this to be we're gonna
在这里，我将其命名为“我们要
call this just you know a beautiful
称它为美丽
Alibaba client okay
阿里巴巴客户还可以
very long-winded but it does give us
很long，但这确实给了我们
what we want to do shows us when we do
我们想做的事告诉我们何时做
now they haven't yet refactor the code
现在他们还没有重构代码
such that is that you wouldn't need a
这样您就不需要
table discovery client so if you've been
表发现客户端，所以如果您去过
using spring cloud for more than a year
使用Spring Cloud超过一年
you might remember that in earlier in
您可能还记得
the first you know the red large
首先你知道红色大
majority of spring clouds life you had
大部分春天的云生活
to use the discovery plan annotation you
使用发现计划注释
have to say at enable discovery client
必须在启用发现客户端说
and then in more recent releases we've
然后在最新版本中
since dropped that requirement by opting
因为通过选择放弃了该要求
in you you know you are considered to
在你里面，你知道你被认为
have opted in opted in by having the
选择加入
depends on the class path and that is
取决于类路径，那是
enough in most cases but for now for not
在大多数情况下足够了，但目前还没有
ghost that's not quite true
鬼不是很真实
so you need at naval discovery client
所以你需要海军发现客户
and then where we start
然后我们开始
okay now will that work let's find out
好吧，现在我们可以找出这项工作了吗
I don't think so service management not
我不认为服务管理不
so much so what we need to do is we need
如此之多，我们需要做的是
to tell our code where to find knuckles
告诉我们的代码在哪里可以找到关节
and that's done of course through some
这当然是通过一些步骤完成的
properties that we store here in we
我们存储在这里的属性
stripped out properties so we want knock
去掉属性，所以我们要敲门
offs config server I guess we need the
关闭配置服务器，我想我们需要
dependency first don't we here we go
首先要依赖我们不是在这里
let's just bring in both dependencies
让我们引入两个依赖
that explains why we didn't get very far
这就解释了为什么我们没有走的太远
at all so we say knock post equals
所以我们说敲门柱等于
localhost 80-48 I'm gonna say not close
本地主机80-48我要说不关闭
server come on config okay knuckles and
服务器来配置好关节和
this would be config survivors okay and
这将是配置幸存者，然后
like that good so there's our our
那样的好，所以我们的
configuration for knuckles what else do
转向节的配置还有什么用
we need I guess that's it that's it
我们需要我想就是这样
that's enough to tell it where to find
足以告诉它在哪里可以找到
our registry so let's go ahead and
我们的注册表，让我们继续
restart and we've got this long-winded
重新启动，我们已经this了
but you know unique name
但是你知道唯一的名字
all right so it's up and running it's
好吧，它启动并运行了
now connected to knockoffs so let's see
现在已经连接到仿冒品，让我们来看看
there we are a beautiful Alibaba client
那里我们是一个美丽的阿里巴巴客户
great we have one healthy instance count
太好了，我们只有一个健康的实例计数
right there it is and we can draw a
就在那，我们可以画一个
configuration now I have no
现在配置我没有
configuration yet but you know we can
配置尚未完成，但您知道我们可以
get that so let's let's first all let me
明白了，让我们首先让我
inject the discoverer Klein here and
在这里注入发现者克莱因，
we'll demonstrate what that looks like
我们将演示它的外观
so let's use the discovery client
因此，让我们使用发现客户端
listener
听众
let me an event listener app book case
让我来一个事件监听器应用书柜
you ready event public void use
您已准备好事件公共无效使用
discovery client okay let's just
发现客户端好吧，我们只是
demonstrate what that looks like so this
演示一下看起来像这样
would be a very simple thing discovery
将是一件非常简单的事情
client
客户
okay this dot discovered client dot get
好吧，这个点发现了客户点
instances and well let's just get the
实例，好吧，让我们来
Serbs names there you go get services
塞尔维亚人的名字在那里得到服务
dot for each and I'm gonna just log out
每个点都有，我要注销
each service name as I see it voila
每个服务名称，如我所见，瞧
all right there's my updated code
好的，这是我的更新代码
injecting the discovered client
注入发现的客户端
okay you can see when it starts up it
好的，您可以看到它何时启动
says bootiful your Baba able to follow
说你的爸爸能跟随我
the bubble client and client all right
泡沫客户和客户都可以
there we go there's our there's our
我们去那里我们那里我们那里
service instances and so on that's it
服务实例等等
that's working as you'd expect and you
就像您期望的那样工作，并且您
know all the rest applies as well you
知道其余的一切同样适用
could do client-side load balancing for
可以为
route if you wanted to do that for
路线，如果你想这样做
example you could say at load balanced
您可以说负载均衡的示例
on your rest template and that would do
在你的休息模板上，那会做
the right thing there and so on okay now
正确的东西在那里，好吧，现在
for configuration
用于配置
well configuration is kind of
很好的配置是
interesting we can store configuration
有趣的是我们可以存储配置
in Knuckles I'm gonna say configuration
在指关节，我要说的是配置
I mean I mean configuration files and we
我的意思是我的意思是配置文件，我们
can change them just like you would with
可以像您对它们进行更改一样
a config server and you know I think
配置服务器，你知道我认为
this is actually in some ways a little
实际上在某些方面
bit more a little bit more slick than
比它更光滑一点
the config server so let's try it out
配置服务器，让我们尝试一下
okay we're gonna create a file called a
好吧，我们要创建一个名为a的文件
what is our spring application name go
我们的春季申请名称是什么
to bootstrap here go create this
在这里引导去创建这个
property file dot properties okay and
属性文件的点属性还可以，
we're gonna call it a property file
我们将其称为属性文件
properties for resolution of cloud elite
云精英解决方案的属性
Oh
哦
key and secret okay
关键和秘密好吗
now you can store yamo HTML text right
现在您可以存储yamo HTML文本了
and this would be good for Florida I
这对佛罗里达我来说是好事
guess we could easily we could plug in a
猜想我们可以轻松地插入
a image banner resolver somehow that
图片横幅解析器
loaded from here for example because now
例如从这里加载，因为现在
that this is API but for our purposes to
这是API，但出于我们的目的
get it to do what we expect it to do for
让它做我们期望做的事
for the purposes of properties we can
就属性而言，我们可以
store properties okay so what I'm gonna
存储属性好，那我该怎么办
do something to say first of all when I
首先要说些什么
start up on port 8081
在8081端口启动
instead of 8080 just to prove that's
而不是8080只是为了证明那是
working and then I want to have some
工作，然后我想要一些
configuration so I can find Ally cloud I
配置，以便我可以找到Ally cloud
want to authenticate now of course
当然要立即进行身份验证
obviously by the time this video is done
很明显，当这部影片完成时
and aired I will have long since deleted
和播出，我将早已删除
these credentials so I you know not that
这些凭据，所以我不知道
any of you would ever go after my my
你们中的任何一个都会追随我的
credentials but just so you know okay so
凭据，但这样您就知道了
there's the key ally cloud key and
有关键的盟友云密钥，
whoops secret okay so that's my key and
哦，秘密好吧，这就是我的钥匙，
secret and I'm gonna use that in my
秘密，我将在我的
application so these are just gonna be
应用程序，所以这些只是
two properties that are and I could also
是的两个属性，我也可以
do things like sort of protocol zero
做类似零协议的事情
right all that configuration that I
对我所有的配置
would normally store my property files
通常会存储我的属性文件
in my application that properties all of
在我的应用程序中，所有属性
that would live here actually more most
其实住在这里最多
conveniently but for now since I have
方便，但现在因为我有
auto-completion
自动完成
in my IDE and I wanna be able to see the
在我的IDE中，我希望能够看到
stuff working we'll go ahead and we'll
东西工作，我们将继续，我们将
leave it there but we want to keep the
留在那里，但我们要保持
distinguishing stuff the stuff that I
区分我的东西
want it to be centralized and kept
希望它被集中并保持
outside of get I want that to be here
在获取之外我希望那个在这里
okay so I'll hit publish it says I've
好的，所以我会点击发布，说我已经
created the configuration why it's in
创建配置的原因
red which is kind of like you know my my
红色，有点像你知道我的
my blood pressure spikes just a just a
我的血压峰值只是一个
hair every time I see a red font in a
每次我看到红色字体
dialog because it tells me something was
对话，因为它告诉我某些事情是
wrong but why that's in red and yeah
是错的，但是为什么是红色的
there's a nice satisfying green checkbox
有一个令人满意的绿色复选框
not quite sure we'll hit okay
不太确定我们会成功吗
and we can go back now now keep in mind
现在我们可以回去了，请记住
we can see the historical versions if we
我们可以看到历史版本
go here this is called the data ID is
去这里叫做数据ID是
called a beautiful client a little fob
叫一个漂亮的客户一个小白鸟
that a bootiful alibaba client that
一个可恶的阿里巴巴客户
properties and we have nothing yet but
物业，我们除了
if I go back and change this value again
如果我返回并再次更改此值
so
所以
hit edit and message equals oh okay
点击编辑，消息等于哦，好吧
or bleeding publish so I can see the
或流血发布，所以我可以看到
Delta right the current value that's
Delta对当前值为
right convenient and we go back here and
方便，我们回到这里，
let's see listening query oh I have to
让我们看看收听查询哦，我必须
do the group as well don't I
我也做小组吗
and the group is default booth isn't
而该组是默认展位不是
come on
来吧
default group capital letters and this
默认组大写字母和这个
so we go here
所以我们去这里
okay there we go so we can see once
好吧，我们去，所以我们可以看到一次
you've been very specifically we've
你一直很特别
you've got to make sure not to fat
你必须确保不胖
finger that goop goop value there once
手指那只咕go值一次
you've done that you're given the sort
您已经完成了排序工作
of historical sequence or the values
历史序列或值
right and this is sort of like what you
对，这有点像你
get when you have get in the spring Club
当你进入春季俱乐部时得到
config server but it's just nice to have
配置服务器，但是很高兴
it more sort of like front and center
它更像前面和中央
you can you can explicitly roll back to
您可以明确回滚到
this particular configuration set you
这种特殊的配置设置你
can see the details you know you can do
可以看到您知道可以做的细节
all sorts of you can see there's an
各种各样的你可以看到有一个
insert thing and whatever okay very
插入东西，什么都可以
interesting now we have our
有趣的是，现在我们有了
configuration we have any we haven't
我们有没有的配置
even used it yet so let's just let's get
甚至还用过，所以让我们开始吧
back to using it in our config we want
回到我们想要的配置中使用它
to connect to
连接到
Holly cloud okay so let's go back to our
Holly cloud好吧，让我们回到我们的
palm that XML we're bringing the objects
掌心着XML，我们带来了对象
service object storage service out of
服务对象存储服务超出
the it's there and we're gonna say
它在那里，我们要说
secret
秘密
ally cloud secret key and I think I
盟友云密钥，我想我
called it ally cloud secret and X is key
称它为盟友云秘密，X是关键
okay and I called it a where did I call
好吧，我称它为哪里
it caon
它cañon
details it is a leak lads secret Nelly
细节，这是一个小伙子的秘密Nelly
club no that doesn't help at all it's
俱乐部，那完全没有帮助
called key and then secret hopefully
叫钥匙，然后希望秘密
that's representative what we need so
这就是我们需要的代表
Ali Club Key Club secret very cool so we
阿里俱乐部钥匙俱乐部的秘密很酷，所以我们
got that now and of course in order to
现在知道了，当然是为了
talk to Ellie Cod I will need to give it
与Ellie Cod交谈，我需要给它
a region and that region will be the you
一个地区，那个地区将是你
know it's gonna be where we find our are
知道它将成为我们找到自己的地方
we know which version of Ally cloud are
我们知道哪个版本的Ally cloud
we using right so we're gonna go back to
我们使用正确的，所以我们要回到
here I'm going to say OSS endpoint I'm
在这里我要说的是OSS端点
gonna point it to HTTP OSS u.s. West one
将其指向HTTP OSS美国西部一号
Ally
盟国
UHN Ali calm okay I think that's it
UHN Ali冷静好吧，我想就是这样
Ali you there you go I think that's a
阿里，你去那儿，我认为那是一个
the code there u.s. West something okay
那里的代码我们西部有些好
there we go there's our nestle
我们去那里有我们的巢
configuration now to connect to Alibaba
现在配置以连接到阿里巴巴
cloud so we're using knockos to do
云，所以我们正在使用kickos
service registrations and discovery and
服务注册和发现以及
we're using it now to store
我们现在用它来存储
configuration including credentials
包括凭证的配置
things like things that I don't want
像我不想要的东西
laying around in my code especially in
放在我的代码中，尤其是在
get you know available for the world to
让您了解全世界
see and now I can use any cloud let's do
看到，现在我可以使用任何云了
that let's do it we've got the
让我们做到这一点，我们已经
configuration for connectivity and for
连接和配置
authentication off set up let's go ahead
身份验证已关闭，让我们继续
and write some code that uses the
并编写一些使用
objects object storage service which is
对象对象存储服务
sort of like s3 but it's you know like
有点像s3，但是你知道像
ally cloud okay so component cloud OSS
盟友云还行，所以组件云OSS
listener at event listener application
事件侦听器应用程序中的侦听器
ready event dot class public void and
准备好的事件点类public void和
then what I want to do is I'm gonna use
那我想做的就是用
OSS okay so let's say it throws
OSS好的，所以可以说它抛出了
exception
例外
private final all SS and inject this
私人决赛所有SS并注入
into the constructor and I'm not gonna
进入构造函数，我不会
do anything too fancy here I'm gonna
做任何我想在这里做的事
create a bucket I'm gonna upload a photo
创建一个水桶我要上传照片
I've got a photo
我有一张照片
you know what photo I've got I've got a
你知道我有什么照片吗？
photo of a kitty cat because cats are
小猫的照片，因为猫是
great so here we go so desktop let's see
太好了，我们开始吧，让我们看看台式机
open desktop kitty okay there we go
打开桌面小猫好吧，我们去
cutest kitty ever well let me stick use
最可爱的小猫咪让我坚持使用
kitty on this screen because there's
小猫在这个屏幕上，因为有
they're all cute now I'm gonna copy that
他们都很可爱，我现在要复制
kitty desktop Tcat to my downloads
kitty桌面Tcat到我的下载
directory reservation observed moon
目录保留观察到的月亮
Faldo Baba source main resources you
Faldo Baba的主要资源来源
know Kitty dot jpg that waits in the
知道在其中等待的Kitty点jpg
path path and I don't have to work too
路径路径，我也不必工作
hard to get it
很难得到
I'll just tell spring to inject it now
我现在就告诉Spring注入
obviously you could do file upload you
显然你可以上传文件
could do a multi-part file form upload
可以上传文件的多部分内容
with spring MVC or splitting Webb flux
使用Spring MVC或拆分Webb通量
these are super easy things to do and
这些都是超级容易的事情，
all I'm gonna do is I'm going to say to
我要做的就是对
use this one okay so we'll say no we
用这个好吧，所以我们说不，我们
want to use class path and it's gonna be
想使用类路径，它将
called kitty jpg will tell spring to
叫kitty jpg会告诉春天
provide a pointer to a resource resource
提供指向资源资源的指针
Kitty okay and then store that as well
小猫还可以，然后再存储
private final resource
私人最终资源
add that into the constructor arguments
将其添加到构造函数参数中
and somehow you got to argument I wanted
以及以某种方式你要争论我想要的
one but it doesn't matter we can fix
一个，但没关系，我们可以修复
that easily now what we're gonna do is
现在我们要做的就是
we're gonna say this dot o SS dot we
我们要说这个点或SS点我们
could check if it has a you know there's
可以检查是否有一个你知道有
a bucket or anything like that but all
一个水桶之类的东西
I'm gonna do is I'm going to say create
我要说的是创造
a bucket bootiful ali-baba spring tip
桶战利品阿里巴巴春天提示
okay
好的
that'll give us a value a bucket and
这会给我们带来价值
then in the bucket we're going to put an
然后在水桶中，我们将
object using OSS so this dot OSS put
对象使用OSS，因此该点OSS
object and it'll be bucket dot get name
对象，它将是存储桶点获取名称
Kitty dot jpg and we'll give it a a
小鹰点jpg，我们给它一个
pointer to the file so I guess resource
指向文件的指针，所以我猜资源
that get file is that right we can give
得到文件就是我们可以给予的权利
it a file we can give it an input stream
它是一个文件，我们可以给它输入流
so even better give it an input stream
所以最好给它一个输入流
that's worth generic okay now before we
现在我们值得通用
do this before we run this must take a
为此，我们必须先执行
look at ally cloud so I've got Ali cloud
看盟友云，所以我有阿里云
I've got my ally cloud account here
我的盟友云帐户在这里
let's login to my alien console
让我们登录到我的外星控制台
I'll you in this alley cloud candies
我会在这巷子里的糖果
back-and-forth in the literature
来回的文学
literature doesn't quite work does it
文学不是很有效
because there's this weirdness with a
因为这有点奇怪
login okay
可以登录
go sign in J f K Y so now you can see
请登录J F KY，现在您可以看到
that they have a vast assortment of
他们有各种各样的
services you can click on this you can
您可以点击此服务即可
see all the cool stuff that they've got
看到他们拥有的所有很酷的东西
here a lot of which is supported in
这里有很多支持
spring cloud on the but we are using OSS
春天的云，但我们正在使用OSS
and that is where did I put it object
那就是我把它放在哪里的对象
and storage service click on that why
和存储服务点击那为什么
does this keep dimming my computer now
这是否使我的计算机现在变暗
we'll see that we've got at the moment
我们会看到我们现在有
I've got one bucket called clicking here
我有一个水桶叫点击这里
called
叫
the Buddha father Bob a spring tip
佛祖鲍勃的春天小提示
bucket it's a bit long okay so there you
桶有点长，所以你在那里
go
走
well whenever we got that okay so let's
好吧，只要我们知道了，那么让我们
go ahead and run this code one more time
继续运行此代码一次
this time it should connect successfully
这一次它应该成功连接
it should authenticate with a li cloud
它应该通过李云进行身份验证
and I should be able to use
我应该能够使用
automatically through the auto
通过自动
configured client some of the
配置客户端的一些
interesting services Victor compelling
有趣的服务Victor引人注目
services in a Lee Clow all righty let's
Lee Clow中的服务好吧，让我们
see what we got
看看我们得到了什么
refresh refresh there we go Buddha Pali
刷新刷新那里我们去佛祖巴利
Baba spring tip bucket if I look at the
爸爸春天小费桶，如果我看着
files open this up there we go how about
文件打开它，我们去怎么样
that huh so with that my friends we
恩，和我的朋友们一样，
looked at a and you can see that you can
看着一个，你可以看到你可以
even see the URL but what's this kitty
甚至看到网址，但是这只小猫是什么
cat would be accessible if you wanted to
如果您愿意，可以使用cat
be time looked at you know how to use
是时候看着你知道如何使用
alibaba's some of alibaba's really
阿里巴巴的一些阿里巴巴的
interesting stuff with spring and spring
春天和春天有趣的东西
cloud and spring but-- we did not get to
云和春天，但-我们没有去
look at robert rocket mq we'll do that
看看罗伯特·火箭火箭，我们会做到的
next time i hope and we didn't get to
下次我希望，我们没有去
look at double which is a service
看这是一项服务的双重
framework which is a whole other whole
一个整体的框架
other oprah and we'll get into that one
其他奥普拉，我们将进入那个
as well that's a good one too but we did
也是很好的，但是我们做到了
get to look at a lot of really
去看很多真的
compelling things here and i I love that
引人注目的东西，我喜欢
there's so much good open source stuff
有太多好的开源东西
coming from the Alibaba team and they're
来自阿里巴巴团队，他们是
they're keen on making this stuff
他们热衷于制作这种东西
generally available and they want
一般可用，他们想要
you know they're out there turning their
你知道他们在外面转
documentation into English and making it
将文件翻译成英文并制作
as accessible as possible for those of
对于那些
us who don't speak the language and I
我们不会说这种语言的我
really appreciate it and I hope you will
非常感谢，希望您能
as well these these technologies were
这些技术也是
born of scale demand very few people
有规模需求的人很少
have right there's just nobody that
有没有人
really can talk about this kind of scale
真的可以谈论这种规模
except save for perhaps Google or
除了为Google或
Facebook I mean these are insane levels
Facebook我的意思是这些都是疯狂的水平
of scale and and so they built things
规模，所以他们建造了东西
that you know they don't have to share
你知道他们不必分享
with us and and you know I'm sure Google
和我们一起，你知道我确定Google
in casebook have had to solve similar
在案例册中不得不解决类似问题
problems and Netflix they also solve
问题和Netflix他们也解决了
several problems Netflix did the world a
Netflix为世界带来的几个问题
big favor when they open sourced a lot
他们开源时大受欢迎
of the sort of internal machinery that
那种内部机械
allowed them to scale to those links
允许他们扩展到那些链接
that they did the heights that they did
他们达到了自己的高度
so in the same vein I think we have a
同样，我认为我们有一个
very interesting opportunity to learn
非常有趣的学习机会
from the proverbial Giants and literal
从谚语巨人和文字
and actual Giants of the cloud like
和云的实际巨人像
Alibaba so um thank you so much and with
阿里巴巴嗯非常感谢你
that my friends we'll see you next time
我的朋友们下次见
you
您